{"Linux operating system":[{"question":"Which command is used to rename files and directories?","option_a":"rn","option_b":"mv","option_c":"cp","option_d":"rn-dir","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is searching syntax?","option_a":":/string","option_b":":r filename","option_c":"Vi","option_d":"vi apple.txt","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What will be the out put of - linux command : $grep ʹhelloʹ ist_file.txt?","option_a":"Searches hello in the ist_file.txt and outputs/returns the lines containing 'hello'","option_b":"Show the ip of local machine","option_c":"Show the DNS of local machine","option_d":"Show the home directory","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the character begins with the first line in any shell script?","option_a":",","option_b":",","option_c":",","option_d":",","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which command should be run first before executing shell script?","option_a":"Chmod + x","option_b":"Chmod +r","option_c":"Chmod +w","option_d":"chmod+rwx","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which command is used to delete files and directories on Linux and Unix?","option_a":"Del","option_b":"mv","option_c":"cp","option_d":"rm","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which command is used to copy files and directories?","option_a":"CP","option_b":"CD","option_c":"CC","option_d":"Copy","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Acronym for sudo in linux is ______","option_a":"su","option_b":"superuser does","option_c":"superuser do","option_d":"super do","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is scripting?","option_a":"File editor","option_b":"To execute bunch of command","option_c":"ImageEditor","option_d":"vi editor","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the key combination used to move screen down one page in linux terminal?","option_a":"Ctrl + I","option_b":"Alt + F","option_c":"Ctrl+F","option_d":"Alt + I","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which commans the full path to the current directory?","option_a":"CD [option] [directory]","option_b":"cd /usr/sbin","option_c":"PWD [option]","option_d":"Cd/","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which command used displays calendar of current month?","option_a":"$cal","option_b":"$ data","option_c":"$id","option_d":"$ date + %T","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which editor display oriented text editor based on the pine message composer?","option_a":"Joe","option_b":"CD","option_c":"Vi","option_d":"Pico","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Who is developed the VI editor?","option_a":"Bill gates","option_b":"Charles Babbage","option_c":"Bill Joy","option_d":"Simon Franklin","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which command used reveals the current logged in user?","option_a":"$tty","option_b":"$id","option_c":"$id root","option_d":"$ whoami","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which Linux command list the content of all sub directory?","option_a":"ls~","option_b":"ls*/","option_c":"ls/","option_d":"ls../","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which linux commands gives you your IP address in your network?","option_a":"Hostname","option_b":"Hostname -l","option_c":"Host-l","option_d":"Hostname - i","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Write the Linux command to remove all the permission to the user and group on the directory ‘softwareʹ?","option_a":"chmod ug - rwx software","option_b":"chmod ug - a software","option_c":"chmod ug - A software","option_d":"chmod ug - Rwx software","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one of the following is the directory separator in Linux?","option_a":",","option_b":",","option_c":",","option_d":",","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which Linux command is used to get all FQDNs(Fully Qualified Domain Name) of the host system?","option_a":"Hostname - i","option_b":"Hostname - b","option_c":"Hostname - a","option_d":"Hostname - A","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Printer and Scanner":[{"question":"Which device has a rigid plastic housing that is replaceable, recyclable and reusable?","option_a":"Toner cartridge","option_b":"Developer roller","option_c":"Developer blade","option_d":"Stirring blade","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which code is split into two halves?","option_a":"QR Code","option_b":"Pen type reader","option_c":"Barcode","option_d":"MFD","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which device includes fax features?","option_a":"Scanner","option_b":"MFD","option_c":"Printer","option_d":"Plotter","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which condition we need to change the toner in printer?","option_a":"Printer installation","option_b":"Empty toner","option_c":"Paper jam","option_d":"Speed of printing","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which technology is particularly used in barcode wand reader and barcode slot reader?","option_a":"Camera based reader","option_b":"Laser scanner","option_c":"QR code scanner","option_d":"Pen type reader","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the main objective of VIRUS scanning?","option_a":"Detection of the live system running on network","option_b":"Discovering the IP address of the target system","option_c":"Discovering the services running on target system","option_d":"Detection of spyware in a system","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the main advantage of dot matrix printer?","option_a":"Speed","option_b":"To make carbon copy","option_c":"Colour print","option_d":"Photo print","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which device includes the functionality of multiple devices in one?","option_a":"MFD","option_b":"Scanner","option_c":"Printer","option_d":"Plotter","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which technology used in drum scanner?","option_a":"Contact image sensor","option_b":"LEDs","option_c":"Flat bed method","option_d":"Photo multiplier tube","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the print speed of line dot matrix printer?","option_a":"10 to 75 cps","option_b":"50 to 550 cps","option_c":"More than 1000 cps","option_d":"More than 1000pps","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the another name of F1 button in passbook printer?","option_a":"Offline button","option_b":"Power button","option_c":"Eject button","option_d":"Online button","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How is ink transferred to paper in inkjet printers?","option_a":"Boiling ink","option_b":"Crystal","option_c":"Motorized pump","option_d":"Screen deflect ink","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is an Input device?","option_a":"Printer","option_b":"Plotter","option_c":"Scanner","option_d":"Monitor","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What allows you to print on both sides of the paper?","option_a":"Duplexer","option_b":"Fuser","option_c":"Toner","option_d":"Paper swapping unit","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the printing speed of large laser printer?","option_a":"150ppm","option_b":"200ppm","option_c":"250ppm","option_d":"300ppm","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the function of ready button ON in pass book printer?","option_a":"to receive data","option_b":"Printer is in PR2 mode","option_c":"Printer is paused","option_d":"Printer is an ESC","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which protocol assigns IP addresses in network printer?","option_a":"ftp","option_b":"DHCP","option_c":"udp","option_d":"POP","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which printer having ethernet port?","option_a":"Network printer","option_b":"Serial port printer","option_c":"USB printer","option_d":"Parallel port printer","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of ADF in scanner features?","option_a":"Automatic Delete File","option_b":"Automatic Document Feeder","option_c":"All Document Feeder","option_d":"Anyway Document Feeder","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of QR Code?","option_a":"Quick Result Code","option_b":"Quadratic Response Code","option_c":"Quick Response Code","option_d":"Quick Relay Code","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which device used to print graphical outputs by computer on a paper?","option_a":"Input processing unit","option_b":"Output processing unit","option_c":"Printer","option_d":"Plotter","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of CIS scanner?","option_a":"Continuous Image Sensor","option_b":"Contact Image Sensor","option_c":"Convert Image Sensor","option_d":"Cathode Image Sensor","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which connection is ideal for scanning high resolution images?","option_a":"Fire wire","option_b":"USB","option_c":"SCSI","option_d":"Parallel","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of OPC in laser printer?","option_a":"Organic Print Control drum","option_b":"Organic Photo Conductor drum","option_c":"Oriented Print Control drum","option_d":"Original Print Control drum","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which printer is an impact printer?","option_a":"Inkjet printer","option_b":"Thermal printer","option_c":"Line matrix printer","option_d":"Electro- photographic printer","answer":"C","notes":""}],"Monitor and Sound Card":[{"question":"What is the another name of touch pad?","option_a":"Keypad","option_b":"Notepad","option_c":"Wordpad","option_d":"Trackpad","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is the most expensive part of the projector?","option_a":"Lens","option_b":"Cable connectors","option_c":"Fan","option_d":"Rectifier","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is full form of MIDI in sound card?","option_a":"Musical Instrument Digital Interface","option_b":"Multi Instrument Digital Interface","option_c":"Musical Instrument Double Interface","option_d":"Multi Instrument Digital Interchange","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the sound frequency range?","option_a":"20KHz to 200KHz","option_b":"5KHz to 50KHz","option_c":"20Hz to 20KHz","option_d":"2KHz to 12KHz","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of EGA in Monitor?","option_a":"Electrical Graphics Array","option_b":"Enrich Graphics Array","option_c":"Electro Static Graphics Array","option_d":"Enhanced Graphics Adapter","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is full form of SNR in Sound Quality?","option_a":"Symbol-to-Noise Ratio","option_b":"Signal-to-Noise Ratio","option_c":"Source-to-Noise Ratio","option_d":"Sound-to-Sound Ratio","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is RGB in LCD projector?","option_a":"Red Gray Black","option_b":"Red Green Blue","option_c":"Red Gray Brown","option_d":"Red Green Brown","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is measuring unit of sound?","option_a":"Frequency","option_b":"ohms","option_c":"Farad","option_d":"Decibel","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which display each pixel in the picture corresponds with a transistor?","option_a":"CRT","option_b":"LCD","option_c":"Monochrome tube","option_d":"Vacuum tube","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is the component of sound Card?","option_a":"Video card","option_b":"DAC","option_c":"Graphic card","option_d":"Light pen","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What we called vibration that compress of air or other substances?","option_a":"Picture","option_b":"Video","option_c":"Light","option_d":"Sound","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the purpose of display card?","option_a":"Sending graphics data input unit","option_b":"Receiving graphics data from output devices","option_c":"Receiving graphics data input devices","option_d":"Sending graphics data to output unit","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is sets to full screen in OLED monitor?","option_a":"","option_b":"","option_c":"","option_d":"","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the significance of sampling rate in case of sound card?","option_a":"More sampling rate means more accuracy","option_b":"More sampling rate means low accuracy","option_c":"Less sampling rate means more accuracy","option_d":"Less sampling rate means low accuracy","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used to clean the projector lens?","option_a":"Water","option_b":"Isopropyl alcohol","option_c":"Colin","option_d":"Soap Oil","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which frequency is support for tweeter speaker?","option_a":"Low frequency","option_b":"Mid-range frequency","option_c":"Very low frequency","option_d":"High frequency","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the highest quality sampling bit in sound cards?","option_a":"8-bit","option_b":"4-bit","option_c":"32-bit","option_d":"16-bit","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which colour used for microphone symbol in audio system?","option_a":"Pink","option_b":"Orange","option_c":"Black","option_d":"Green","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which monitors are capable of displaying up to 16 million colours with a resolution of 800 x 600 on 14-inch monitors and up to a 1200 x 1600 resolution on a 20-inch?","option_a":"VGA","option_b":"tft","option_c":"CRT","option_d":"SVGA","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of CRT?","option_a":"Cartridge Ray Tube","option_b":"Common Red Tube","option_c":"Cathode Ray Tube","option_d":"Common Ray Tube","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which monitor used for 64 colors?","option_a":"CGA","option_b":"VGA","option_c":"EGA","option_d":"SVGA","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which device have touch pad is an inbuilt?","option_a":"Desktop","option_b":"Laptop","option_c":"Server","option_d":"Workstation","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"In which port of sound card in typical desktop pc microphone is connected?","option_a":"Pink","option_b":"Yellow","option_c":"Black","option_d":"Green","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"LCDʹs operating frequency range is ________","option_a":"10Hz to 60Hz","option_b":"50Hz to 70Hz","option_c":"30Hz to 60Hz","option_d":"80Hz to 90Hz","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is maximum resolution of SVGA monitor?","option_a":"160x100","option_b":"1280x1024","option_c":"720x400","option_d":"640x350","answer":"B","notes":""}],"UPS and MODEM":[{"question":"What is the purpose of Switched Mode Power Supply (SMPS)?","option_a":"To convert AC supply of a frequency to AC supply of different frequency","option_b":"To convert AC supply into DC supply","option_c":"To convert DC supply into AC supply","option_d":"To convert unregulated DC supply into regulated AC supply","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of ISA?","option_a":"Industry Standard Architecture","option_b":"Indian Standard Architecture","option_c":"Input Standard Address","option_d":"Industry Standard Address","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the meaning of IRQ?","option_a":"Input Request","option_b":"Importance Request","option_c":"Information Request","option_d":"Interrupt Request","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which transmission mode is also known as start-stop mode?","option_a":"Synchronous","option_b":"Asynchronous","option_c":"Character","option_d":"Communication","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the meaning of MODEM?","option_a":"Modern Electronic Machine","option_b":"Modulator and Demodulator","option_c":"Modern Development Machine","option_d":"Modulator and Converter","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Identify the card required for computer communications.","option_a":"Sound card","option_b":"Graphics card","option_c":"NIC","option_d":"Motherboard","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which adapter card that converts the analog video signal into digital card?","option_a":"Video card","option_b":"Graphics card","option_c":"Video / graphic card","option_d":"Video capture card","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"When the process requests for a DMA transfer?","option_a":"Then the process is temporarily suspended","option_b":"The process continues execution","option_c":"Another process gets executed","option_d":"Process is temporarily suspended & Another process gets executed","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is full form of AGP?","option_a":"Analog Graphics Port","option_b":"Analog Grid Port","option_c":"Accelerated Graphics Port","option_d":"Accelerated Grid Port","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which transmission mode, two independent clocks are used on either side?","option_a":"Successive","option_b":"Synchronous","option_c":"Asynchronous","option_d":"Protocol","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the minimum time period for check water level of the battery?","option_a":"Every 50 days","option_b":"Every 15 days","option_c":"Every 5 days","option_d":"Every 30 days","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the function of relays in UPS?","option_a":"Voltage increase","option_b":"Voltage decrease","option_c":"Electrically operate switch","option_d":"Current decrease","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which battery do not require any kind of regular maintenance?","option_a":"Automobile batteries","option_b":"Lead acid batteries","option_c":"SMF batteries","option_d":"Nickel-cadmium batteries","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is used for to smooth out and filter fluctuations in voltage in UPS?","option_a":"Battery","option_b":"Relay","option_c":"Electrolytic capacitor","option_d":"Fans","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is affected by irregular maintenance?","option_a":"Battery","option_b":"Relay","option_c":"Fan","option_d":"Capacitor","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which transmission mode, the transmitter and the receiver use the same clock?","option_a":"Synchronous","option_b":"Asynchronous","option_c":"Communication","option_d":"Character","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which device is used with critical load like hospital intensive care unit where a temporary power failure can cause lot of inconvenience?","option_a":"UPS","option_b":"lps","option_c":"SMPS","option_d":"SCS","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which primary cell have the lowest voltage?","option_a":"Lithium","option_b":"Zinc chloride","option_c":"Mercury","option_d":"Carbon zinc","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name for convert digital signal to analog signal?","option_a":"Modulation","option_b":"Demodulation","option_c":"Bypass","option_d":"Encapsulation","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which device provide 25 mbps of band width an internet connection via cable?","option_a":"Router","option_b":"Hub","option_c":"Switch","option_d":"Modem","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which device is used for to send and receive data over telephone lines?","option_a":"Router","option_b":"Hub","option_c":"Switch","option_d":"Modem","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used in the rotating type UPS system to supply the mains?","option_a":"Alternator","option_b":"DC motor","option_c":"DC generator","option_d":"Battery bank","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of DVR card?","option_a":"Dual Visual Recorder","option_b":"Digital Video Recorder","option_c":"Digital Visual Reader","option_d":"Dual Video Reader","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the frequency range of broadband satellite communication method?","option_a":"4GHz - 6GHz","option_b":"11GHz -14GHz","option_c":"5GHz -10GHz","option_d":"1GHz - 5GHz","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the transmission speed of satellite communication method?","option_a":"1mbps to 3mbps","option_b":"30mbps to 40mbps","option_c":"1mbps to 10mbps","option_d":"50mbps to 100mbps","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of MOV in UPS?","option_a":"Main Oxide Varistors","option_b":"Metal Oxide Voltage","option_c":"Metal Oxide Varistors","option_d":"Metal Oxide Price","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used for checked by battery capacity?","option_a":"Electric tester","option_b":"Neon tester","option_c":"Volt meter","option_d":"Load tester","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the correct application of offline UPS?","option_a":"Protect workstations, terminals, or equipment above 1 kVA","option_b":"Protect workstations, terminals, or equipment above 5 kVA","option_c":"Protect workstations, terminals, or equipment above 3 kVA","option_d":"Protect workstations, terminals, or equipment below 1 kVA","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of wi-fi?","option_a":"Wiring Fidelity","option_b":"Wireless Frequency","option_c":"Wiring Frequency","option_d":"Wireless Fidelity","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is most commonly used battery type in a UPS?","option_a":"Dry cell","option_b":"Flat cell","option_c":"Round cell","option_d":"Valve -regulated lead acid battery","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the efficiency of standby UPS type?","option_a":"High","option_b":"Very high","option_c":"Low","option_d":"Low-medium","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the measured unit of UPS output rating?","option_a":"voltage","option_b":"amperes","option_c":"volt ampere","option_d":"Farad","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the life expectancy of battery in UPS?","option_a":"10-20 years","option_b":"5-10 years","option_c":"8-10 years","option_d":"3-5 years","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of IR in wireless communication?","option_a":"Inner Range","option_b":"Infrared","option_c":"Inner Red","option_d":"Infra Range","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used to configure computer peripherals?","option_a":"Jumpers","option_b":"DIP switches","option_c":"I/O address","option_d":"DMA","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used to describe the maximum oscillation rate of an electronic signal?","option_a":"Bit rate","option_b":"Baud rate","option_c":"Hub","option_d":"Switch","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the example of battery backup?","option_a":"CPU","option_b":"UPS","option_c":"SMPS","option_d":"Electrolyte","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Who is introduced for PCI?","option_a":"HCL","option_b":"Intel","option_c":"Lenovo","option_d":"Dell","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which test is used to ascertain whether the battery plates are defective?","option_a":"Open volt test","option_b":"Cadmium test","option_c":"High discharge test","option_d":"Specific gravity test","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the character must be a battery electrode?","option_a":"A semi conductor","option_b":"An insulator","option_c":"A good conductor","option_d":"A bad conductor","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of Mbps in modem?","option_a":"Mega Bites Per Second","option_b":"Mega Binary Per Second","option_c":"Mega Bits Per Second","option_d":"Mega Booting Per Second","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of DSL in modem?","option_a":"Dual Signal Line","option_b":"Digital Subscriber Line","option_c":"Digital Signal Layer","option_d":"Dual Signal Layer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used in electrolytes, to prevent local action in battery?","option_a":"Pump water","option_b":"Distilled water","option_c":"Tap water","option_d":"Mineral water","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one network connection provide 1000 mbps band width?","option_a":"Gigabit ethernet","option_b":"Router","option_c":"Gateway","option_d":"Hub","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of SMF battery?","option_a":"Special Multi Free","option_b":"Sealed Maintenance Free","option_c":"Special Mains Free","option_d":"Sealed Multi Free","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of DMA?","option_a":"Digital Memory Access","option_b":"Direct Memory Adder","option_c":"Direct Memory Access","option_d":"Digital Memory Adder","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which component makes an online UPS different from offline UPS?","option_a":"Charge controller","option_b":"Battery","option_c":"Static transfer switch","option_d":"AC/DC rectifier","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is provides uninterrupted power to the load?","option_a":"SMPS","option_b":"UPS","option_c":"Rectifier","option_d":"Regulator","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is general category of modern UPS system?","option_a":"Serious UPS","option_b":"Neutral UPS","option_c":"Line interactive UPS","option_d":"Extreme UPS","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Identify the device that is required to connect two DTEs directly.","option_a":"Modem","option_b":"Switch","option_c":"Null-Modem","option_d":"Router","answer":"C","notes":""}],"Computer Update and Troubleshoot":[{"question":"What is magneto optic disk?","option_a":"Primary storage","option_b":"Secondary storage","option_c":"Removable disk","option_d":"Input device","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is failure, if we got 5 beeps in beep code method?","option_a":"RAM","option_b":"CPU","option_c":"Video card","option_d":"CMOS battery","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which disk consist of a circular disk and coated with thin metal?","option_a":"Magnetic","option_b":"Compact","option_c":"Optical","option_d":"Hard","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of DAT drive?","option_a":"Dual Audio Tape","option_b":"Digital Automatic Tape","option_c":"Dual Automatic Tape","option_d":"Digital Audio Tape","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the permanent memory of a computer?","option_a":"RAM","option_b":"CD-ROM","option_c":"ROM","option_d":"CPU","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the memories is primarily used to store machine microcode, desktop bootstrap loaders, and video game cartridges?","option_a":"Mask-programmed ROM","option_b":"Static -RAM","option_c":"Dynamic -RAM","option_d":"Non-Programmed ROM","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of the boot loader software used in Windows Vista and later releases of the Microsoft OS?","option_a":"WINLOAD.EXE","option_b":"NTLDR","option_c":"LILO","option_d":"GRUB","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of CD-ROM?","option_a":"Critical Disk-Read Only Memory","option_b":"Compact Disk-Random Only Memory","option_c":"Critical Disk-Radius Only Memory","option_d":"Compact Disk-Read Only Memory","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the cheapest memory device in terms of costs/bit?","option_a":"Semi conductor memory","option_b":"Magnetic disks","option_c":"Compact disks","option_d":"Magnetic taps","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which drive combine the HDD and SSD technologies into one drive?","option_a":"SSD","option_b":"Hard disk drive","option_c":"Hybrid hard disk drive","option_d":"SCSI","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which tool organizing files on a disk?","option_a":"Disk","option_b":"Folder","option_c":"Cluster","option_d":"Record","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What could cause a fixed disk error?","option_a":"No-CD installed","option_b":"Bad RAM","option_c":"Slow processor","option_d":"Incorrect CMOS setting","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is failure, if beeps repeating endlessly in beep code?","option_a":"RAM","option_b":"CMOS","option_c":"video card","option_d":"CPU","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the measuring unit for, access time in storage devices?","option_a":"Milli seconds","option_b":"Nano seconds","option_c":"Micro seconds","option_d":"Pico seconds","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is kind of CD-ROM?","option_a":"Optical disk","option_b":"Magnetic disk","option_c":"Magneto-optical disk","option_d":"Opto mechanic disk","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which disk has a smallest storage capacity?","option_a":"Zip disk","option_b":"Hard disk","option_c":"Floppy disk","option_d":"Compact disk","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is example of ZIP drive?","option_a":"An output device","option_b":"An input device","option_c":"Removable disk storage","option_d":"A software","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the example of floppy disk?","option_a":"Primary storage","option_b":"Semiconductor storage","option_c":"Tertiary storage","option_d":"Bootable storage","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one of the memories must be refreshed many times per second?","option_a":"EPROM","option_b":"Static -RAM","option_c":"ROM","option_d":"Dynamic RAM","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a special purpose register of microprocessor?","option_a":"Program counter","option_b":"Instruction register","option_c":"Accumulator","option_d":"Temporary register","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is built with tertiary storage?","option_a":"A lot of money","option_b":"Unremovable media","option_c":"Removable media","option_d":"Secondary storage","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of SCSI in drive?","option_a":"Similar Computer System Interface","option_b":"Small Computer System Interconnector","option_c":"Similar Converter System Interface","option_d":"Small Computer System Interface","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of POST?","option_a":"Post On Self Test","option_b":"Physical Self Test","option_c":"Power-On Self Test","option_d":"Power-On-Save Text","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which device is used for you can test keyboard cable continuity?","option_a":"Wattmeter","option_b":"Voltmeter","option_c":"Digital multimeter","option_d":"Ammeter","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which recording format used by DAT drive?","option_a":"Parallel data storage","option_b":"Digital data storage","option_c":"Serial data storage","option_d":"Scanned data storage","answer":"B","notes":""}],"Tablet  Smart devices":[{"question":"Which device inbuilt for advanced features and typically cellular phones?","option_a":"dslr","option_b":"smart phones","option_c":"tablets","option_d":"note pads","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is tablet PC brand?","option_a":"bpl","option_b":"SIMON","option_c":"APPLE","option_d":"Zenith","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of the OS consist of android 4.1, 4.2 and 4.3?","option_a":"Lollipop","option_b":"Kitkat","option_c":"Jelly bean","option_d":"Oreo","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What will happen if RTC ((Real Time Clock) chip on tablet motherboard get corrupted?","option_a":"Then there will be no date or time in the tablet phone and the set can even get dead","option_b":"It will not get charge","option_c":"Display will not come","option_d":"Sound will not work properly","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is the mobile app development tool?","option_a":"Safari","option_b":"Orfox","option_c":"Orkut","option_d":"Phonegap","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is an open source mobile OS?","option_a":"Black Berry OS","option_b":"iphone OS","option_c":"Android OS","option_d":"Microsoft OS","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which subsystem provides radio transmission between mobile station and switching center?","option_a":"Base station subsystem","option_b":"Network sub system","option_c":"Operation sub system","option_d":"Internet system","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is smart phone brand?","option_a":"ONIDA","option_b":"Phillips","option_c":"bpl","option_d":"One plus","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What expansion types do must motherboard support?","option_a":"MCA,PCI","option_b":"ISA, EISA","option_c":"ISA, PCI, AGP","option_d":"ISA, VESA, PCI","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the Most common screen size of tablet PC?","option_a":"5 inches","option_b":"10 inches","option_c":"14.5 inches","option_d":"16.5 inches","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is an IOS?","option_a":"Windows OS","option_b":"iphone OS","option_c":"Linux OS","option_d":"Android OS","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the power consumption of tablet PC?","option_a":"40-50 watts","option_b":"15-30 watts","option_c":"5-10 watts","option_d":"1-5 watts","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which part is available for in smartphone?","option_a":"Keypad","option_b":"Microphone","option_c":"Mouse","option_d":"Projector","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is type of motherboard?","option_a":"atx","option_b":"CT","option_c":"ctx","option_d":"ptx","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which device is used for, to connect expansion slots and interface cards?","option_a":"Ports","option_b":"Peripheral devices","option_c":"Mother board","option_d":"System bus","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is a mobile phone OS?","option_a":"Android","option_b":"windows xp","option_c":"red hat","option_d":"Windows 98","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which is manages the switching function in GSM?","option_a":"Base station subsystem","option_b":"Network and switching subsystem","option_c":"Operation support subsystem","option_d":"Internet system","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of the circuit board contained within the processor of the computer?","option_a":"SMPS","option_b":"Motherboard","option_c":"HDD","option_d":"RAM","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which device included features like web and email access, special software and hardware?","option_a":"laptop","option_b":"Notepad","option_c":"Smartphone","option_d":"tablet","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the version of icecream sandwich?","option_a":"Android 7.0","option_b":"Android 6.0","option_c":"Android 5.1","option_d":"Android 4.0","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What type of battery used for tablet?","option_a":"Nickel-cadmium","option_b":"NIMH","option_c":"Lithium polymer","option_d":"Lithium-ion","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used for input in tablet?","option_a":"digital pen","option_b":"keyboard","option_c":"Mouse","option_d":"scanner","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is part of tablet PC?","option_a":"SMPS","option_b":"touch screen","option_c":"CPU","option_d":"UPS","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is a icecream sandwich in smart phone?","option_a":"Android OS","option_b":"Gram app","option_c":"Computer OS","option_d":"Phonegap","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is SOC in electronic devices like smartphones?","option_a":"System-on-a-Chip","option_b":"System-in-a-Chip","option_c":"System-of-a-Chip","option_d":"System-over-a-Chip","answer":"A","notes":""}],"Internet and Web Browser":[{"question":"What is the full form of http?","option_a":"High Tension Transfer Protocol","option_b":"High Text Transfer Protocol","option_c":"Hyper Text Transfer Protocol","option_d":"Hyper Text Transducer Program","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which option used for, to send an email?","option_a":"Compose","option_b":"Subject","option_c":"Body","option_d":"From","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the main view of Section 23 of Information Technology Act 2000?","option_a":"Suspension of license","option_b":"Procedure for grant or rejection of license","option_c":"Renewal of license","option_d":"Application for license","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one of the cloud concepts is related to sharing and pooling the resources?","option_a":"Polymorphism","option_b":"Virtualization","option_c":"Abstraction","option_d":"Activation","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of BCC in email?","option_a":"Block Carbon Copy","option_b":"Bit Carbon Copy","option_c":"Brown Carbon Copy","option_d":"Blind Carbon Copy","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is COOKIE?","option_a":"A small piece of information that is stored in the client browser and used to identify or recognize the user","option_b":"Business software","option_c":"Search engine","option_d":"Social media","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of ISP?","option_a":"Indian Service Provider","option_b":"Internet Service Provider","option_c":"Internet Server in Physical","option_d":"Internet Service Programmer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is web browser?","option_a":"adobe reader","option_b":"Tally","option_c":"google chrome","option_d":"photoshop","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When the indian parliament passed the IT act?","option_a":"1990","option_b":"1992","option_c":"2000","option_d":"2005","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of WWW?","option_a":"World Wind Web","option_b":"World Wide Writer","option_c":"Website Wind Writer","option_d":"World Wide Web","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which cloud is a composition of two or more clouds?","option_a":"Private cloud","option_b":"Public cloud","option_c":"Cloud client","option_d":"Hybrid cloud","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is called protecting data from online attacks, deletions and malwares?","option_a":"Physical security","option_b":"Cyber security","option_c":"Cyber attack","option_d":"Virus","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of CPI in cloud computing?","option_a":"Count Provider Interface","option_b":"Cloud Process Indicator","option_c":"Cloud Provider Interface","option_d":"Cloud Pointing Interface","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is main function of a internet browser?","option_a":"Software to browse a source code","option_b":"Software to browse virus and malware","option_c":"It takes in the HTML code and parses it to create the DOM (Document Object Model) tree","option_d":"Provide operating system and security","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is e-mail?","option_a":"erasable mail","option_b":"Easy Mail","option_c":"Electronic Mail","option_d":"Message easily","answer":"C","notes":""}],"Network Components":[{"question":"Which is the first public packet-switched computer network?","option_a":"ARPANET","option_b":"ERNET","option_c":"SKYNET","option_d":"DARPANET","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Identify the network security device that monitors traffic to or from your network.","option_a":"Firewall","option_b":"Gateway","option_c":"Router","option_d":"Virus checker","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"How do fiber optics work?","option_a":"By connecting and transferring energy","option_b":"By remitting and subtracting power from other fiber optics","option_c":"By using Light pulses to transfer data","option_d":"By converting sound waves in to binary code","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How many standard of RJ-45 wiring?","option_a":"1","option_b":"2","option_c":"3","option_d":"4","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which cable has an inner conductor and an outer conductor separated by insulation?","option_a":"Twisted-pair cable","option_b":"Fiber-optic cable","option_c":"Coaxial cable","option_d":"Microwave cable","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Usually CAT 5 Cable has how many Pair?","option_a":"1 pair","option_b":"2 pairs","option_c":"3 pairs","option_d":"4 pairs","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which port is used to connect RJ 45 connector?","option_a":"Ethernet","option_b":"USB port","option_c":"HDMI port","option_d":"Centronics port","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of the device which sends information on computer network?","option_a":"Receiver","option_b":"Transmitter","option_c":"Sender","option_d":"Medium","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of LAN?","option_a":"Light Area Network","option_b":"Local Area Network","option_c":"Light Average Network","option_d":"Left Area Network","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Computer network which spans a large physical area connecting several sites of an organization across cities, countries and continents is known as?","option_a":"LAN","option_b":"WAN","option_c":"M.A.N.","option_d":"pan","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Where BNC connectors are used?","option_a":"Television","option_b":"Laptop","option_c":"Mobile","option_d":"Tablet","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is used as a high speed network media?","option_a":"Shielded twisted pair cable","option_b":"Unshielded twisted pair cable","option_c":"Co-axial cable","option_d":"Fiber optic cable","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which cable is used for connecting hub to hub?","option_a":"Coaxial cable","option_b":"Roll-over cable","option_c":"Cross-over cable","option_d":"Straight-through cable","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following represented the fastest data transmission speed?","option_a":"Gbps","option_b":"Mbps","option_c":"Kbps","option_d":"Bps","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the frequency range of Wi-Fi?","option_a":"2.4 GHz and 5GHz","option_b":"2.9GHz and 5GHz","option_c":"3.4GHz and 5GHz","option_d":"4.4GHz and 5GHz","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which transmission technique is used by mobile network?","option_a":"Microwave","option_b":"Radio","option_c":"Infrared","option_d":"Ultra high frequency","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which topology is connected along single piece of n/w cable?","option_a":"Bus topology","option_b":"Ring topology","option_c":"Star topology","option_d":"Mesh topology","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which type of twisted pair cable is used for protecting from electronic noise?","option_a":"Unshielded twisted pair","option_b":"Shielded twisted pair","option_c":"Shift twisted pair","option_d":"Serial twisted pair","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the purpose of using parity bits in computer network?","option_a":"Encryption of data","option_b":"To transmit faster","option_c":"To detect errors","option_d":"To identify the user","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which type of network supports by category 5 cable?","option_a":"100BASE-TX","option_b":"90BASE-TX","option_c":"80BASE-TX","option_d":"70BASE-TX","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the ground station in VSAT communication?","option_a":"hub","option_b":"http","option_c":"Multiplexer","option_d":"Repeater","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which topologies have two or more combination?","option_a":"Star topology","option_b":"Bus topology","option_c":"Ring topology","option_d":"Hybrid","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the color code of first Pin in T-568B standard?","option_a":"White/orange","option_b":"White","option_c":"Orange","option_d":"White/green","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which information is communicated in data communication?","option_a":"Sender","option_b":"Receiver","option_c":"Message","option_d":"Protocol","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which topology uses multipoint connection?","option_a":"Ring topology","option_b":"Bus topology","option_c":"Mesh topology","option_d":"Star topology","answer":"B","notes":""}],"Network Protocols":[{"question":"What is the full form of IPV4?","option_a":"Internet Process Versus 4","option_b":"Internet Protective Version 4","option_c":"Internet Protocol Version 4","option_d":"Internet Play Version 4","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Switches works on which layer of OSI model?","option_a":"Physical layer","option_b":"Network layer","option_c":"Data link layer","option_d":"Session layer","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which layer in OSI model assigns internet protocol(IP) addresses?","option_a":"Data link layer","option_b":"Session layer","option_c":"Presentation layer","option_d":"Network layer","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which layer in OSI model use MAC for communication?","option_a":"Physical layer","option_b":"Data link layer","option_c":"Session layer","option_d":"Network layer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"How many types of transmission mode are there?","option_a":"1","option_b":"2","option_c":"3","option_d":"4","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of IGRP?","option_a":"Interior Gateway Routing Protocol","option_b":"Internet Gate Routing Protocol","option_c":"Interface Google Refresh Protocol","option_d":"International Gateway Routing Protocol","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"How many bits are there in IPV6?","option_a":"16 bits","option_b":"32 bits","option_c":"64 bits","option_d":"128 bits","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is not a networking device?","option_a":"Keyboard","option_b":"Router","option_c":"Firewall","option_d":"Switch","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the purpose of DHCP server?","option_a":"To provide storage for email","option_b":"To translate URLs to IP address","option_c":"To translate IPv4 address to MAC address","option_d":"To provide an IP addresses to the client computers","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following network device amplify the input signal?","option_a":"Keyboard","option_b":"Mouse","option_c":"Printer","option_d":"Repeater","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Hub works on which layer of OSI model?","option_a":"Physical layer","option_b":"Data link layer","option_c":"Network layer","option_d":"Transport layer","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"How many types of network switches are there?","option_a":"1","option_b":"2","option_c":"3","option_d":"4","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of TCP/IP?","option_a":"Telnet Control Protocol / Internet Protocol","option_b":"Transfer Control Protocol / Interface Protocol","option_c":"Telephone Central Protocol / Internet Protocol","option_d":"Transmission Control Protocol / Internet Protocol","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is network security tool?","option_a":"Keyboard","option_b":"Mouse","option_c":"Joy-stick","option_d":"Anti-virus software package","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"HTTP protocol functions at which layer of the OSI model.","option_a":"Session layer","option_b":"Presentation layer","option_c":"Data link layer","option_d":"Application layer","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not correct?","option_a":"Telnet is general purpose client-server program","option_b":"Telnet lets user access an application on a remote computer","option_c":"Telnet can also be used for file transfer","option_d":"Telnet can be used for remote login","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"In which layer of OSI network architecture, the routing is performed?","option_a":"Data link layer","option_b":"Network layer","option_c":"Session layer","option_d":"Transport layer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of SMTP?","option_a":"Simple Message Transfer Protocol","option_b":"Simple Mail Transmission Protocol","option_c":"Simple Mail Transfer Protocol","option_d":"Simple Message Transmission Protocol","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of device which receive information in computer network?","option_a":"Receiver","option_b":"Sender","option_c":"Transmitter","option_d":"Input","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which country TCP/IP was developed?","option_a":"America","option_b":"India","option_c":"China","option_d":"Japan","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the maximum number of IP addresses that can be assigned to hosts on a local subnet that uses the 255.255.255.224 subnet mask?","option_a":"14","option_b":"15","option_c":"16","option_d":"30","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the equipment used to allow home computer to connect to the internet?","option_a":"monitor","option_b":"CPU","option_c":"Internet","option_d":"Modem","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following layer is not present in the TCP/IP model?","option_a":"Transport layer","option_b":"Application layer","option_c":"Network layer","option_d":"USB layer","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"In OSI model which layer is responsible for routing?","option_a":"Session layer","option_b":"Data link layer","option_c":"Presentation layer","option_d":"Network layer","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"How many bits are there in IPV4?","option_a":"16 bits","option_b":"32 bits","option_c":"64 bits","option_d":"128 bits","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Identify the TCP/IP protocol used in sending and receiving email.","option_a":"ftp","option_b":"smtp","option_c":"TCP/IP","option_d":"MIME","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"How many layers in OSI model?","option_a":"4","option_b":"5","option_c":"6","option_d":"7","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of layer-4 in TCP/IP model?","option_a":"Internet layer","option_b":"Host-to-Host-layer","option_c":"Network layer","option_d":"Application layer","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the another name of static routing?","option_a":"Non-adaptive routing","option_b":"Basic-input output system","option_c":"Power on self test","option_d":"Upgrade","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which layer is responsible for process delivery?","option_a":"Network layer","option_b":"Transport layer","option_c":"Session layer","option_d":"Datalink layer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is another name of set of rules?","option_a":"Message","option_b":"Input data","option_c":"Protocol","option_d":"Output data","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"In OSI model which layer organise data bits into data frames?","option_a":"Network layer","option_b":"Data link layer","option_c":"Physical layer","option_d":"Transport layer","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is denial of software (DoS) in network security?","option_a":"Protocol","option_b":"Threat","option_c":"Hard-disk","option_d":"Motherboard","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is the lowest layer of TCP/IP model?","option_a":"Network access layer","option_b":"Internet layer","option_c":"Host to host layer","option_d":"Application layer","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which process converts analog signal to digital signal?","option_a":"Modulation","option_b":"De-modulation","option_c":"Quanting","option_d":"Sampling","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"How computer process data into information by working exclusively with?","option_a":"Multimedia","option_b":"Word","option_c":"Numbers","option_d":"Character","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which command is used to determining the ip address of a particular device?","option_a":"NETSAT","option_b":"TRACERT","option_c":"NET","option_d":"ipconfig","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following hub does not require power source?","option_a":"Active hub","option_b":"Passive hub","option_c":"Intelligent hub","option_d":"Moderate hub","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which protocol is used to send mail messages?","option_a":"ftp","option_b":"http","option_c":"smtp","option_d":"Html","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of VPN?","option_a":"Very Poor Network","option_b":"Virtual Private Network","option_c":"Virtual Public Network","option_d":"Virtual Private Naming","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Repeater works on which layer of OSI model?","option_a":"Layer 1","option_b":"Layer 2","option_c":"Layer 3","option_d":"Layer 4","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of server which uses FTP protocol for data transfer?","option_a":"File server","option_b":"TCP/IP model","option_c":"OSI model","option_d":"Transfer server","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a standard protocol?","option_a":"JAVA","option_b":"php","option_c":"http","option_d":"MS-Office","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of device which is used to connect a different type of network LAN?","option_a":"Printer","option_b":"Scanner","option_c":"Router","option_d":"UPS","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is a tool used for network troubleshooting?","option_a":"Hammer","option_b":"File","option_c":"Wire stripper","option_d":"Clamp-meter","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"You need to subnet a network into 5 subnets, each with at least 16 hosts. Which classful subnet mask would you use?","option_a":"255.255.255.192","option_b":"255.255.255.224","option_c":"255.255.255.240","option_d":"255.255.255.248","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of fourth layer in OSI model?","option_a":"Data link layer","option_b":"Network layer","option_c":"Transport layer","option_d":"Application layer","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of computer which is connected to the internet cable?","option_a":"Client computer","option_b":"Protocol","option_c":"Hyperlink","option_d":"Uniform Resource Locator","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Choose the port number of FTP.","option_a":"23","option_b":"21","option_c":"110","option_d":"143","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is used to select best path to transfer data?","option_a":"Modulation","option_b":"Routing","option_c":"Paging","option_d":"Defragmentation","answer":"B","notes":""}],"Sharing Resources":[{"question":"Which one is not a Anti-virus?","option_a":"Kasper sky","option_b":"Wordpress","option_c":"Quick-heal total security","option_d":"Norton 360 standard","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What type of site is facebook?","option_a":"Social networking","option_b":"Internet layer","option_c":"Artificial intelligence","option_d":"Commercial","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"When was internet first invented?","option_a":"In 1969","option_b":"In 1960","option_c":"In 1970","option_d":"In 1980","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Who maintains the domain name system?","option_a":"Distributed database system","option_b":"A single server","option_c":"A single computer","option_d":"A computer network","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not a internet service Provider?","option_a":"Airtel","option_b":"Vodafone","option_c":"Idea","option_d":"Google","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Network Troubleshooting":[{"question":"Which tool is correct for remote management?","option_a":"WAN management","option_b":"Memory management","option_c":"Cryptography","option_d":"Bandwidth","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is another name of packet capture?","option_a":"Packet sniffing","option_b":"Packet forwarding","option_c":"Packet handling","option_d":"POST","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Why one time password (OTP) is safe?","option_a":"Easy to generate","option_b":"Cannot be shared","option_c":"Used for one Transaction only","option_d":"Complex encrypted password","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the function of a router?","option_a":"Forward the packet to the uplinks","option_b":"Provide data back up","option_c":"Auto update","option_d":"Scanning","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is computer and network surveillance?","option_a":"To check network status","option_b":"To implement various command","option_c":"To restart network device","option_d":"To monitoring of data & computer activity","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which transmission media is capable of having a much higher bandwidth?","option_a":"Coaxial","option_b":"Twisted pair cable","option_c":"Plastic","option_d":"Fibre optic","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which devices used in telecommunication that connects two network with different transmission protocol together?","option_a":"Gateway","option_b":"Switch","option_c":"Hub","option_d":"Modem","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which process aids network administrators and analysts in gathering network data, allowing them to measure performance variables and identify potential issues or risks?","option_a":"Network protection","option_b":"Windows update","option_c":"Network performance monitoring","option_d":"Windows registry edit","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which model is used by network switch that works on data link layer?","option_a":"osp model","option_b":"OSI model","option_c":"osj model","option_d":"OSK model","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the function of network surveillance?","option_a":"To generate virus","option_b":"To provide backup","option_c":"To monitor data traffic on computers","option_d":"Cryptography","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of device which is used for forward data based on a physical address?","option_a":"Bridge","option_b":"Hub","option_c":"Repeater","option_d":"Router","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Maximum data transfer rate refers to _________.","option_a":"error detection","option_b":"packet switching","option_c":"bandwidth","option_d":"transmission media","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the first step to troubleshoot network problem?","option_a":"Ping","option_b":"Open it","option_c":"Contact to ISP","option_d":"Wait the network problem out","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of network tool that uses to check that all cables have been crimped properly?","option_a":"Toner probes","option_b":"Long-nose plier","option_c":"Wire stripper","option_d":"Cables tester","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is used to protect computer network from internet attack?","option_a":"Server","option_b":"Windows-OS","option_c":"Hard-disk","option_d":"Firewall","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of these is a benefit of virtual network?","option_a":"They have a higher level of security than other remote connections","option_b":"There is no need for any hardware to connect a computer to a network","option_c":"There is no need for any software to connect a computer to a network","option_d":"They stop any errors occurring in the transmission of data in a network","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which software is used to monitor networks on computer and mobile devices?","option_a":"Microsoft outlook","option_b":"Internet explorer","option_c":"Open DNS home VIP","option_d":"Google chrome","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which new feature extends windows defender smart screen by blocking outbound (HTTP and HTTPS) traffic connecting to resources that have a low reputation?","option_a":"Firewall","option_b":"Network protection","option_c":"Antivirus","option_d":"Port scanning","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which command is used in network to trace route?","option_a":"NET","option_b":"TRACERT","option_c":"NBTSTAT","option_d":"ipconfig","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which tool is used in troubleshooting of wireless network?","option_a":"Wireless locator","option_b":"Wi-Fi hot spot","option_c":"Twizzer","option_d":"Cables tester","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of these components is internal to a computer and is required to connect the computer to a network?","option_a":"Modem","option_b":"Network Interface card","option_c":"Switch","option_d":"Hub","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which devices are used for communication and interaction b/w devices on a computer network?","option_a":"Motherboard","option_b":"Networking devices","option_c":"Primary memory","option_d":"Secondary memory","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the another name of firewall?","option_a":"adobe reader","option_b":"ms-access","option_c":"Security-gateway","option_d":"DRAM","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the main function of firewall?","option_a":"Protect","option_b":"Copy","option_c":"Delete","option_d":"Move","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which forces the user to change password at first login?","option_a":"Default behaviour of OS","option_b":"Part of AES encryption practice","option_c":"Device being assured forces the user","option_d":"Account administrator","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Network Security":[{"question":"Identify the hardware device or software application installed on the borderline of a networks to examine and control incoming and outgoing network communications.","option_a":"Firewalls","option_b":"Network server","option_c":"Network monitoring application","option_d":"Active directory service","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Where WPA2 security is used?","option_a":"Ethernet","option_b":"Bluetooth","option_c":"Wi-Fi","option_d":"Computer","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the work of network layer firewall?","option_a":"Frame filter","option_b":"Packet filter","option_c":"Band pass filter","option_d":"Capacitor filter","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which protocol is used for encrypting (coding) data at network level?","option_a":"ip sec","option_b":"HTTPS","option_c":"smtp","option_d":"S/MIME","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is not a strong security protocols?","option_a":"HTTPS","option_b":"SSL","option_c":"smtp","option_d":"SFTP","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of WPA?","option_a":"Wi-Fi Protected Access","option_b":"Wi-Fi Private Area","option_c":"Wi-Fi Protected Area","option_d":"Wi-Fi Private Access","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of SIP?","option_a":"Session Initiation Protocol","option_b":"Secured Initiation Protocol","option_c":"Secure Initiation Protocol","option_d":"Session Integration Protocol","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which permission is must for GPO in order to delegate permission for GPO?","option_a":"Edit users, content, menu","option_b":"Edit group, delete, modify the security","option_c":"Edit group, delete, modify user","option_d":"Edit user, delete, content","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is the least strong security encryption standard?","option_a":"WPA3","option_b":"WPA2","option_c":"WPA","option_d":"WEP","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which attack uses deception and falsehoods to convince others to give up private information, such as an account password?","option_a":"Data theft attacks","option_b":"Malware attacks","option_c":"Insider threat attacks","option_d":"Social engineering attacks","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of SFTP?","option_a":"Secure File Transfer Protocol","option_b":"Secure File Transfer Protocol","option_c":"Secure Folder Transfer Protocol","option_d":"Secure File Transfer Protocol","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which wireless security mode will you suggest for an average person?","option_a":"WEP (Wireless Equivalent Privacy)","option_b":"WPA (Wireless Protected Access)","option_c":"Android Security","option_d":"Wi-Fi direct","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is cipher in cryptography?","option_a":"Copy data","option_b":"Algorithm for performing encryption and decryption","option_c":"Move data","option_d":"Remote management","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which protocol ensures the integrity and security of data that are passing over a network?","option_a":"Firewall","option_b":"Antivirus","option_c":"Pentesting tools","option_d":"Networks-security protocols","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is meant by cryptography?","option_a":"Paragraph writing","option_b":"Disk-checking","option_c":"Disk-cleaning","option_d":"Secret writing","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Server Installation":[{"question":"How many types of groups are in active directory?","option_a":"2","option_b":"3","option_c":"4","option_d":"5","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which hardware is not request for installing window server 2008?","option_a":"Hard-disk","option_b":"Processor","option_c":"Display","option_d":"Scanner","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which option is not correct while configuration of windows server?","option_a":"Time and date setting","option_b":"Provide computer name & domain","option_c":"Configure networking","option_d":"Connect computer to bluetooth","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the next step for server after the window installation?","option_a":"Configuration","option_b":"Updation","option_c":"Upgrade","option_d":"Ping","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not an advantage of client server networks?","option_a":"Traffic congestion","option_b":"Centralised","option_c":"Security","option_d":"Performance","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"How many group scopes are there in active directory?","option_a":"0","option_b":"3","option_c":"5","option_d":"10","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is required to increase data storage capacity and redundancy in server?","option_a":"Multiple Hard Drive","option_b":"Multiple RAM","option_c":"Multiple ROM","option_d":"Multiple processor","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is not a component of active directory?","option_a":"Group policy","option_b":"Internet Information services","option_c":"Distribution groups","option_d":"Security groups","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of powerful central computer on network?","option_a":"Server","option_b":"Client","option_c":"Hub","option_d":"Router","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which program runs on the local machine requesting service from the server?","option_a":"Protocol","option_b":"Client","option_c":"File","option_d":"Data","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which model provides the network service to client to perform task?","option_a":"OSI model","option_b":"TCP/IP model","option_c":"Client-server model","option_d":"Client model","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which type of server is best for a small office?","option_a":"Tower server","option_b":"Rack server","option_c":"Blade server","option_d":"Cloud server","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Who translate domain name to IP address so browser can load internet resources?","option_a":"Active directory","option_b":"Domain name system","option_c":"MS office","option_d":"MS-word","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not found in container structure of active directory?","option_a":"Sites","option_b":"Domain","option_c":"Forest","option_d":"Web","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not a web server?","option_a":"Apache web server","option_b":"IIS web server","option_c":"Nginx web server","option_d":"MS-office","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which company developed active directory?","option_a":"ibm","option_b":"Apple","option_c":"Samsung","option_d":"Microsoft","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of ADDS?","option_a":"Active Directory Domain Service","option_b":"Active Directory Data Service","option_c":"Auto Directory Data Service","option_d":"Adaptive Directory Data Service","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not a type of server?","option_a":"File server","option_b":"Database server","option_c":"Client","option_d":"Print server","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of other group policy setting if one is computer configuration setting?","option_a":"Policy configuration setting","option_b":"Organisational configuration setting","option_c":"Group configuration setting","option_d":"User configuration settings","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is a server?","option_a":"Anti-virus","option_b":"Driver","option_c":"hardware and software","option_d":"Hardware","answer":"C","notes":""}],"Install DNS and RRAS":[{"question":"Which process converts host name into its equivalent IP address?","option_a":"BIOS setup","option_b":"Name resolution","option_c":"Disk clean up","option_d":"Data backup","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Identify the server which keeps DNS updated with a siteʹs correct IP address, even if it changes frequently.","option_a":"Dynamic DNS","option_b":"Authoritative name server","option_c":"Mail transfer agent","option_d":"DHCP","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the name of second part of e-mail address?","option_a":"Password","option_b":"Mail-provider","option_c":"Name of website","option_d":"Domain-name","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of DORA in DHCP?","option_a":"Discover, Offer, Request, Acknowledge","option_b":"Discover, Operate, Reply, Acknowledge","option_c":"Data, Operation, Request, Advantage","option_d":"Direct, Open, Request, Apply","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is assigned by DHCP to the clients?","option_a":"MAC address","option_b":"Url","option_c":"IP address","option_d":"Name","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the type of .com domain?","option_a":"Education institutions","option_b":"Network infrastructure","option_c":"Commercial organisation","option_d":"Government institutions","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the total no. of bits for n/w ID/host for class A n/w?","option_a":"8/24","option_b":"9/24","option_c":"10/24","option_d":"11/24","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which parameter is not assigned by DHCP?","option_a":"Subnet mask","option_b":"Default gateway address","option_c":"Domain name server","option_d":"SSL","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of RRAS?","option_a":"Radio and Radar Access Services","option_b":"Routing and Remote Access Services","option_c":"Ranging and Radio Access Services","option_d":"Remote Ranging Access Services","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is provided to client machine using DHCP?","option_a":"MAC address","option_b":"URL","option_c":"Host name","option_d":"IP address","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the distributed hierarchical naming system for computers?","option_a":"DHCP","option_b":"IPv4","option_c":"DNS","option_d":"Networks","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What can be done using remote access policies?","option_a":"Assign IP to client","option_b":"Apply connection restrictions upon successful authorization","option_c":"Assign MAC address","option_d":"Assign URL","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Who maintains DNS?","option_a":"Dynamic DNS","option_b":"Distributive database system","option_c":"Mail transfer agent","option_d":"DNS resolver","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"How DHCP client and servers communicate on the same subnet?","option_a":"UDP unicast","option_b":"TCP broadcast","option_c":"UDP broadcast","option_d":"TCP unicast","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which domain is used to map an address to a name?","option_a":"Generic domain","option_b":"Main domain","option_c":"Sub domain","option_d":"Inverse domain","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"How many types of DNS- service in network?","option_a":"1","option_b":"2","option_c":"3","option_d":"4","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which OS is used to configure IAS service?","option_a":"windows server","option_b":"Android","option_c":"Mac","option_d":"windows xp","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"How many types of IP address assigned by DHCP?","option_a":"1","option_b":"2","option_c":"3","option_d":"4","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is not a country top level domain?","option_a":".ae","option_b":".br","option_c":".fr","option_d":".ab","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What are the three categories of IPV6 address?","option_a":"Unicast, anycast, multicast","option_b":"Dynamic, red-write and Red only","option_c":"In the Start Of Authority record (SOA)","option_d":"Older applications that are unable to use FQDNʹs","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is private IP address?","option_a":"12.0.0.1","option_b":"168.172.19.39","option_c":"172.15.14.36","option_d":"192.168.24.43","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"DNS database contains _______","option_a":"name server records","option_b":"MAC address range","option_c":"E-mail list","option_d":"IP range","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the level of domain in www.microsoft.com?","option_a":"Top level domain","option_b":"Medium level domain","option_c":"Low level domain","option_d":"Intermediate level domain","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the process followed while assign an IP address to the client by DHCP?","option_a":"AROD","option_b":"DROA","option_c":"ARDO","option_d":"DORA","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a type of DNS services?","option_a":"Automatic DNS","option_b":"Advance DNS","option_c":"Active Directory Service","option_d":"Authoritative DNS","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Windows & Linux Server Configuration":[{"question":"What is meant by roll back of transactions?","option_a":"Recover from previous transaction","option_b":"Update the transaction","option_c":"Delete old records","option_d":"Repeat a transaction","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which port is connected by telnet protocol?","option_a":"TCP port number 21","option_b":"TCP port number 22","option_c":"TCP port number 23","option_d":"TCP port number 24","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"For which operating system absolute telnet is a telnet client?","option_a":"Windows","option_b":"Linux","option_c":"Mac","option_d":"DOS","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following allows to view a webpage?","option_a":"MS-Office","option_b":"web server","option_c":"operating system","option_d":"Internet Browser","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is login shell?","option_a":"One that runs when the user login","option_b":"One that authenticate the user while logging in","option_c":"One that user that belong to the same group","option_d":"One that give no permission","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which service allows a user to log in to another computer on the internet?","option_a":"telnet","option_b":"ftp","option_c":"E-mail","option_d":"use net","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What does CBR stands for the congestion?","option_a":"Constant Bit Rate","option_b":"Control Bit Rate","option_c":"Constant Byte Rate","option_d":"Control Byte Rate","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which internet service allows the user to move a file?","option_a":"ftp","option_b":"telnet","option_c":"use net","option_d":"Time sharing","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which command is used to display the Unix version?","option_a":"Uname-r","option_b":"Name-n","option_c":"Name-t","option_d":"Kernel","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the basic difference between BASH and DOS commands?","option_a":"Bash commands are case sensitive while DOS commands","option_b":"Bash commands are not case sensitive while DOS commands","option_c":"Bash commands does not allow small letters while DOS commands","option_d":"Bash commands does not allow special character while DOS commands","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"A server that can perform no other task beside network service is called?","option_a":"UNO services","option_b":"Dedicated server","option_c":"Committed server","option_d":"Service server","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What are the protocols that web server use to handle requests on the internet?","option_a":"HTTP and HTTPS protocol","option_b":"FTP and TELNET","option_c":"ssh and sms","option_d":"ICMP and IGMP","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which hardware architecture are not supported by red hat?","option_a":"IBM-compatible","option_b":"Alpha","option_c":"Macintosh","option_d":"SPARC","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the time required for a bit to travel from source to destination called?","option_a":"Latency","option_b":"Propagation delay","option_c":"delay","option_d":"Transmission time","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which is an essential part of any backup system?","option_a":"Filter","option_b":"Recovery","option_c":"Security","option_d":"Scalability","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"When RAM does not have enough memory to hold all programs that are executing?","option_a":"etc. partition is used","option_b":"Boot loader is used","option_c":"SWAP space is used","option_d":"Home partition is used","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of following are the web services excepts?","option_a":"jetty","option_b":"Tornado","option_c":"Apache Tomcat","option_d":"Blue Griffin","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following service not use TCP?","option_a":"DHCP","option_b":"smtp","option_c":"http","option_d":"ftp","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is not a proper state of transaction?","option_a":"Partially aborted","option_b":"Partially committed","option_c":"Aborted","option_d":"Committed","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the easiest way of communication now a days?","option_a":"Fax","option_b":"Letter","option_c":"Telegram","option_d":"E-mail","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What command is used to count the total number of lines, words and characters contained in a file?","option_a":"Countw","option_b":"W count","option_c":"WC","option_d":"Count P","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How user can change the default log in shell?","option_a":"Using Ch mod","option_b":"Using chsh","option_c":"Using rmsh","option_d":"Using tchsh","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the another name of remote backup site?","option_a":"primary site","option_b":"Secondary site","option_c":"Tertiary site","option_d":"construction site","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the code of Linux OS?","option_a":"Shell","option_b":"terminal","option_c":"Kernel","option_d":"command","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the function of linux boot loader?","option_a":"It is used for security purpose","option_b":"It is used to load the Linux kernel into main memory","option_c":"it is used for backup","option_d":"It is used for recovery purpose","answer":"B","notes":""}]}